(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-23T21:22:53.964544",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
YO! SAY、夏が 胸を刺激する
YO! SAY, the summer stirs my heart,
生足 魅惑の マーメイド
bare-legged, captivating mermaid.
出す とこ 出して たわわに なったら
Showing what I've got and becoming lush,
本物の 恋 は やれ 爽快っ
real love is so exhilarating!
ゴマ カシ 効か ない 薄着 の 曲線 は
The revealing curves that cannot be faked
確信犯 の しなやか な style!
are a premeditated, graceful style!
耐水性の 気分 に 切り替わる
Shifting into a waterproof mood,
瞬間の 眩し さ は いかがな もの
how is this momentary brilliance?
ココロ まで 脱がされる 熱い 風 の 誘惑 に
Lured by the hot wind that strips even the heart bare,
負け ちゃ って 構わ ない から 真夏 は 不祥事 も キミ 次第
it's okay to give in—midsummer scandals depend on you!
妖精 たち が 夏 を 刺激 する
Fairies make summer exciting,
生足 魅惑の マーメイド
bare-legged, captivating mermaid.
出す とこ 出して たわわに なったら
Showing what I've got and becoming lush,
本物の 恋 が でき そう かい?
can you find true love like this?
キミ じゃ なく て も バテ 気味 に も なる よ
Even if it's not you, I'd get exhausted,
暑い ばっかり の 街 は 憂鬱 で
this stiflingly hot city is so gloomy.
スキ を 見せ たら 不意 に 耳 に 入る
If I show an opening, it unexpectedly catches my ear—
サブ い ギャグ なんか で 涼み たく ない
I don't want to cool down with lame gags!
むせ返る 熱帯夜 を 彩る 花火 の よう に
Like fireworks coloring the sultry tropical night,
打ち上げ て 散る 想い なら この まま 抱き合って 焦がれる まで
if these feelings burst and scatter, let's embrace until we burn up!
妖精 たち が 夏 を 刺激 する
Fairies make summer exciting,
生足 魅惑の マーメイド
bare-legged, captivating mermaid.
出す とこ 出して 素直 に なり たい
I want to be honest and show what I've got,
キミ と ボク と なら it's alright
if it's with you and me, it's alright!
都内 の ビル の 海 じゃ 感情 なくなってる キミ を
You, whose emotions are lost in the sea of city buildings—
冷え た ワイン の 口説き で 酔わせ て とろかし て 差し上げ ましょ う
let me intoxicate and melt you with chilled wine pickup lines!
妖精 たち が 夏 を 刺激 する
Fairies make summer exciting,
生足 ヘソ 出し マーメイド
bare-legged, midriff-baring mermaid.
恋 に かまけ て お 留守 に なる の も
Getting distracted by love and neglecting things
ダイスケ 的 に も オール オッケー!
is totally all right by Daisuke's standards!
YO! SAY、夏 を 誰 と し たく なる ?
YO! SAY, who do you want to spend summer with?
一人寝 の 夜 に you can say good bye
You can say goodbye to lonely nights sleeping alone!
都会 伸びる の 海 じゃ 感情 なくなってる キミ を
You, whose emotions are lost in the sea of city buildings—
冷え た ワイン の 口説き で 酔わせ て とろかし て 差し上げ ましょ う
let me intoxicate and melt you with chilled wine pickup lines!
妖精 たち が 夏 を 刺激 する
Fairies make summer exciting,
生足 ヘソ 出し マーメイド
bare-legged, midriff-baring mermaid.
恋 に かまけ て お 留守 に なる の も
Getting distracted by love and neglecting things
ダイスケ 的 に も オール オッケー!
is totally all right by Daisuke's standards!
YO! SAY、夏 を 誰 と し たく なる ?
YO! SAY, who do you want to spend summer with?
一人寝 の 夜 に you can say good bye
You can say goodbye to lonely nights sleeping alone!
妖精 たち が 夏 を 刺激 する
Fairies make summer exciting,
生足 ヘソ 出し マーメイド
bare-legged, midriff-baring mermaid.
恋 に かまけ て お 留守 に なる の も
Getting distracted by love and neglecting things
ダイスケ 的 に も オール オッケー!
is totally all right by Daisuke's standards!
YO! SAY、夏 を 誰 と し たく なる ?
YO! SAY, who do you want to spend summer with?
一人寝 の 夜 に you can say good bye
You can say goodbye to lonely nights sleeping alone!
はい！というわけで、
Yay! So,
私のライブみんな見に来てくれて、ありがとうございます！
thank you everyone for coming to see my live!
最初からいっぱい踊っちゃったよ、ありがとう！お水飲みながらちょっとお話をしようかなと思います。
I was dancing so much from the start, thank you! I thought I'd chat a bit while having some water.
お水はあっちだ。
The water's over there.
あ、皆さん、ありがとうございます。ありがとうございます。
Ah, everyone, thank you so much. Thank you.
すみません。
Pardon me.
というわけで、あん肝もね、新衣装をね、
So, Ankimo also has a new outfit,
でも可愛いけど。可愛いだろ？可愛いだろ？
but it's cute. Isn't it cute? Isn't it cute?
というわけで、あん肝もね、新衣装をね、おね、ゲットしまして、
So, Ankimo also got a new outfit,
まあ今日だけの新衣装なんですけど、後ろにもあん肝がいるっていう。あん肝もね、増えるものだからしょうがない。ね？
well, it's just a new outfit for today, but Ankimo is there in the back too. Well, Ankimo multiplies too, so it can't be helped, right?
そして今回はですね、え、ときのそら5周年記念ということで、こちらのハッシュタグで、え、つぶやいていただけるとうれしいです！
And this time, well, to commemorate Tokino Sora's 5th anniversary, I'd be happy if you could tweet with this hashtag!
またですね、あ、可愛い、可愛いよね？可愛いよね？あん肝も。
And also, ah, cute, it's cute right? Cute right? Ankimo too.
で、ゲストにはね、ゼロキセの皆さんも後で登場するので、ぜひぜひよろしくお願いします！
And as for guests, the members of Zekise will also appear later, so please look forward to it!
今回もね、ま、知ってる人は知ってるかもしれないんですが、告知もあるので、よろしくお願いいたしますね！
This time too, well, some of you might already know, but there are announcements too, so please look forward to those as well!
というわけで、1曲目踊ったばかりなんですけども、
So, we just finished dancing the first song, but
早速行いていこうと思います！行ってきまーす！
I'll get right into it! Here I go!
あの日見た空 茜色の空を
The sky I saw that day, the sky of a deep red,
ねえ 君は覚えていますか
hey, do you remember?
約束 誓い 初夏の風が包む
A promise, a vow, wrapped in the early summer breeze,
二人 寄り添った
we leaned close together.
無理な笑顔の裏
Behind the forced smiles,
伸びた影をかくまう
we hide our lengthening shadows.
だから 気づかぬふり 再生を選ぶ
So I pretend not to notice and choose to start over.
テーブルの上の 震えない知らせ 待ち続けて
Continuing to wait for the unwavering signal on the table,
空白の夜も 来るはずのない朝も
even on nights of emptiness and mornings that should never come,
全部わかってたんだ
I understood everything.
あの日見た空 茜色の空を
The sky I saw that day, the sky of a deep red,
ねえ 君は忘れたのでしょうか
hey, you must have forgotten.
約束 千切り 初夏の風に消えた
The promise, torn apart, vanished in the early summer breeze.
二人 戻れない
We can't go back.
音も 色も 温度も 半分になった この部屋
The sound, the color, the warmth have all been halved in this room.
今日も散らかしては 揺れ 疲れ 眠る
Today, too, I leave it scattered, swaying, exhausted, falling asleep.
「上手面に嘘いてね 嘘は嫌いで好き」 君の言葉
"Deceive me well, I hate lies but love them," your words
今頃になって 気持は痛いほど
have become painful to the point of ache now,
だから 僕ら さよなら
so we say goodbye.
いつかまたねと 手を振り合ったけれど
We waved goodbye saying we'd meet again someday, but
もう逢うことはないのでしょうか
we probably won't ever meet again, will we?
最後の嘘は 優しい嘘でした
The last lie was a gentle lie.
忘れない
I won't forget.
あの日見た空 茜色の空を
The sky I saw that day, the sky of a deep red,
ねえ いつか思い出すでしょう
hey, you'll remember someday, won't you?
果たせなかった 約束を抱いて
Embracing the unfulfilled promise,
二人 歩き出す
we start walking.
乾いた心で駆け抜ける
I run past you with a thirsty heart.
ごめんね何もできなくて
Sorry, I couldn't do anything.
痛みを分かち合うことさえ
Even sharing our pain with each other
あなたは許してくれない
You won't even forgive.
無垢に生きるため振り返らず
In order to live purely, without looking back
背中向けて去ってしまう
I turn my back and leave.
on the lonely rail
私ついていくよ
I'll follow you.
どんな辛い世界の闇の中でさえ
No matter how painful the darkness of the world is
きっとあなたは輝いて
Surely you will shine
超える未来の果て
Beyond the limits of the future,
弱さ故に魂こわされぬように
So that my soul won't be broken by weakness.
God knows...
乾いた心で駆け抜ける
I run past you with a thirsty heart.
ごめんね何もできなくて
Sorry, I couldn't do anything.
痛みを分かち合うことさえ
Even sharing our pain with each other
あなたは許してくれない
You won't even forgive.
無垢に生きるため振り返らず
In order to live purely, without looking back
背中向けて去ってしまう
I turn my back and leave.
on the lonely rail
私ついていくよ
I'll follow you.
どんな辛い世界の闇の中でさえ
No matter how painful the darkness of the world is
きっとあなたは輝いて
Surely you will shine
超える未来の果て
Beyond the limits of the future,
弱さ故に魂こわされぬように
So that my soul won't be broken by weakness.
my way 重なるよ
my way, our paths overlap
いまふたりに God bless...
Now, God bless the two of us...
届けて熱くなる想いは
My passionate feelings reaching out
現実溶かしてさめようと
Melt reality, as if to cool down
会いたい気持ちに理由はない
There's no reason for wanting to see you
あなたへあふれだす Lovin' you
Overflowing towards you, Lovin' you
せめて美しい夢だけを
At least while painting only beautiful dreams
描きながら 追いかけよう
Let's chase after them
for your lonely heart
やめて嘘はあなたらしくないよ
Stop it, lying isn't like you
目を見てこれからのことを話そう
Look into my eyes and let's talk about the future
私覚悟してる
I'm prepared
暗い未来だって
Even for a bleak future
強くなって運命変えられるかもね
Become strong and you might even change fate
my wish かなえたいのに
Though I want my wish to be granted
すべては God knows...
God knows everything...
あなたがいて 私がいて
You are here, and I am here
ほかの人は消えてしまった
All the other people have disappeared
淡い夢の美しさを描きながら 傷なぞる
Tracing scars while sketching the beauty of our fleeting dream
だから私ついていくよ
So I'll follow you
どんな辛い世界の闇の中でさえ
No matter how painful the darkness of the world is
きっとあなたは輝いて
Surely you will shine
超える未来の果て
Beyond the limits of the future,
弱さ故に魂こわされぬように
So that my soul won't be broken by weakness.
my way 重なるよ
my way, our paths overlap
いまふたりに God bless...
Now, God bless the two of us...
渇いた心で駆け抜ける
Running through with a thirsting heart
ごめんね 何もできなくて
I'm sorry I couldn't do anything
痛み分かち合うことさえ あなたは許してくれない
Even sharing our pain, you won't allow me to do
無垢に生きるため振り向かず
Living purely without looking back
はい！というわけで、2曲歌わせていただきました！
Yes! So, we just sang two songs!
そしてね、歌っている間に、衣装が変わりました！すごいね！すごいね！
And while I was singing, my outfit changed! Amazing, right? Amazing!
これね、リハーサルで見てた時にね、あっ、やっぱりスタッフルームは神なんだって、すごいと思いながらね、リハーサルしてました。
When I saw this during rehearsal, I thought, 'Ah, the staff really are gods,' and practiced thinking how amazing it was.
すごいよ！めちゃ嬉しい！どう？衣装、ドレスンなったよ！
It's amazing! I'm so happy! How is it? It became a dress!
イェーイ！というわけで、あの、いつもの衣装、そしてドリーム衣装、そして一番新しくなった衣装ということで、
Yay! So, we have my usual outfit, my dream outfit, and the newest outfit,
今まで5周年でね、きてきた衣装をね、どんどん早着替えをしてきてみました。いかが、いかがだったですか？
and I did quick changes into the outfits I've worn over these 5 years. How... how was it?
そしてですね、なんとなんと！なんと今日わ、本日ニューアルバム「Sign」のリリースが決まったんです！イェーイ！こちら！
And guess what! Today, the release of my new album 'Sign' has been decided! Yay! Here it is!
いや、これは引っさげてのライブも楽しみだな！
Man, I'm really looking forward to the live tour featuring this!
というわけで、すごいね、なんか、そうそうたる方々に作っていただいたみたいで、たくさん聞いていただけてるみたいで感謝でいっぱいです。ぜひぜひ皆さん楽しんで聞いてください。そして、
So, it's amazing, it seems like so many stellar creators made songs for it, and I'm full of gratitude. Please everyone enjoy listening to it. And,
こちら！リリースイベント バーチャルお話し会開催決定！というのも開催しますので、ぜひよろしくお願いします。1回目のお楽しみはなんと今日なんですけど、
this! A virtual talk event release event is decided! We'll be holding that too, so please look forward to it. The first one is actually today,
まあまあまあまあ、その、その次がね、まあ、まだまだ締め切りまでありますので、ぜひぜひみんな見てもらえると嬉しいな。イベントの詳細チェックしてね！
well, well, as for the next one, there's still time until the deadline, so I'd be really happy if everyone checks it out. Check the event details!
んー、やあ、なんかもう、すでに感無量なんだけど、ちょっと
Hmm, man, I'm already feeling so overwhelmed, but wait,
次の曲もね、歌っていきたいなと思います。お水を飲んでくるね。
I'd like to sing the next song too. I'm going to go drink some water.
お水が飲んでくるね。やあ、次の曲からはね、え、アルバムの曲を初めてここで披露したいなと思っている
I'll go drink some water. Man, starting from the next song, uh, I want to perform songs from the album here for the first time,
ので、ぜひぜひそちらの方聞いていただけたら嬉しいです。それでは聞いてください。アルバム「Sign」から、「ピットして！マーマレード」！
so I'd be really happy if you listened to it. Now then, please listen. From the album 'Sign', 'Pit Shite! Marmalade'!
こんなに こんなに 叶えたいんだ 強く願って願うだけ夢になった
So much, so much, I want to make it come true. Wishing strongly, just wishing turned it into a dream.
だからしっかりとピットして！マーマレード 私がんばるよがんばるからね
That's why pull yourself together firmly! Marmalade. I will do my best, because I'll do my best.
よっしゃ！get up! stand up! run up! grow up!
Yossha! get up! stand up! run up! grow up!
時に満面で 時におちゃらけて 時に凛々しく
Sometimes smiling fully, sometimes playing around, sometimes dignified
コロコロ変わる 空模様みたい どれもちやんと空だし
Like the ever-changing sky, each one is truly the sky
繋ぐ 星と星のフレーズ 私と君のやりとりが線になる
Connecting stars to stars in a phrase, the interaction between you and me becomes a line
素敵！ ロマンチックで ドラマチック 星座になって そして歌になる
Wonderful! Romantic and dramatic. Becoming a constellation and then becoming a song
日進月歩って言えるほど たくましくできてないかもしれない せいぜいトライアルアンドエラーっていう感じ？ i my me！
Maybe I'm not strong enough to call it daily progress. At best, it's trial and error? I my me!
ススメ！ ナヤマ！ カンガエテ！
Advance! Worry! Think!
ねえ、これが私でいいかな？ いいでしょ？
Hey, is it okay if this is me? It's fine, right?
ちょっとやそっとじゃ 揺らがないの こんぐらいはラタラタ笑えちゃうの
It won't shake easily over little things. About this much, la-ta-la la-ta-la, I can laugh it off
笑えたら 次に行こう 気づいてる？ ちょっと成長してるよ！
Once we can laugh, let's move on to the next. Have you noticed? I've grown a little bit!
キュートに キュートに 甘いだけじゃなくて ほんのり ほんのり ほろ苦いの
Cute, cute, not just sweet. Slightly, slightly bitter
だって合言葉は ピットして！マーマレード 君に会えるまで 次は何しよう？
Because our watchword is pull yourself together! Marmalade. Until I can meet you, what shall we do next?
よっしゃ！get up! stand up! run up! grow up!
Yossha! get up! stand up! run up! grow up!
キュートに キュートに 甘いだけじゃなくて ほんのり ほんのり ほろ苦いの
Cute, cute, not just sweet. Slightly, slightly bitter
だって合言葉は ピットして！マーマレード 君に会えるまで 次は何にしよう？
Because our watchword is pull yourself together! Marmalade. Until I can meet you, what shall we do next?
よっしゃ！get up! stand up! run up! grow up!
Yossha! get up! stand up! run up! grow up!
こんなに こんなに 叶えたいんだもん
There's so much I want to make come true!
強く願って 願うだけ 夢になった
Dreaming simply by wishing so strongly—
そうだから しっかり ピットして！マーマレード
That's why I'll snap into it! Marmalade!
私がんばるよ がんばるからね
I'm gonna do my best, because I'll work hard!
よっしゃ！ get up！ stand up！
Alright! Get up! Stand up!
run up！ grow up！
Run up! Grow up!
時には真面目で 時にはチャラけて 時には凛々しく
Sometimes serious, sometimes playful, sometimes dignified,
コロコロ変わる空模様みたい どれもちゃんとした空だし
like the ever-changing weather, each one is truly the sky.
繋ぐ星と星のフレーズ 私と君のやり取りが線になる
The phrase connecting stars, our banter becomes a line.
素敵！ロマンチックでドラマチック 星座になってそして歌になる
Wonderful! Romantic and dramatic, becoming a constellation, then a song!
日進月歩って言えるほど たくましくできてないかもしれないけど
Maybe we can't call it leaps and bounds just yet,
せいぜいトライアンドエラーっていう感じか？ i my me！
but it's more like trial and error, right? I my me!
ススメ！ナヤメイ カンガエテ！
Go ahead! Worry and think!
ねぇ、これが私でいいかな？ いいでしょ！
Hey, is it okay if this is me? It's fine, right?
ちょっとやそっとじゃ揺らがないの こんくらいは la-ta-la la-ta-la
It won't waver over just anything, about this much is la-ta-la la-ta-la
笑えちゃうの 笑えたら次に行こう
making me smile. If I can smile, let's move on to the next.
気づいてる？ちょっと成長してるよ！
Have you noticed? I'm growing a little bit!
キュートにキュートに甘いだけじゃなくて ほのぼのほのぼのほろ苦いの
Not just cute and sweet, but gently, faintly bittersweet.
だから合言葉は ピットして！マーマレード
That's why our watchword is snap into it! Marmalade!
君に会えるまで次は 何しよう？
What shall we do next until I can see you?
よっしゃ！ get up！ stand up！ run up！ grow up！
Alright! Get up! Stand up! Run up! Grow up!
細部に凝って真心込めて 届けたいんだもん
Putting care into the details and pouring my sincerity, I want to deliver it to you!
一期一会かもしれないけど 繋がれ、空みたく
It might be a once-in-a-lifetime encounter, but let's connect, like the sky.
どんな服を着て街に出よう どんな髪型を試そう
What clothes should I wear out into town? What hairstyle should I try?
ひとつひとつ君に見てほしいから …ほんとうだよ！
I want you to see every single one of them... seriously!
君はどうだろう もしもが いっぱい いっぱい 連なって
What about you? With so many "what ifs" linked together,
奇跡が いっぱい いっぱい 起きちゃって 見たことない 景色 になる
and countless miracles happening, it becomes a sight we've never seen.
君と私が 作った 景色 だよ とってもとっても 嬉しい ん だ
It's a scenery that you and I made, and I'm so, so happy.
だからね 本当に本当に ありがとう 、 だ ！ 君が くれる その 声 で
That's why, thank you so, so much! With that voice you give me,
マーマレード どんな 色 に でも なれる コート に 溶かす メロディー
Marmalade, melting melodies into a coat that can become any color,
や 食パン に るるりズム で 楽しさ メーター は 上がって いく
or rhythms spreading on toast, the happiness meter keeps rising.
ススメ ！ ススメ ！ モット ユケ ！ ねぇ 、 だから 私 は 私 で いたい の 。
Go on! Go on! Keep going! Hey, that's why I want to stay myself.
こんなに こんなに 叶え たい ん だ 強く 願っ て 願う だけ 夢 に なっ た
There's so much I want to make come true! Dreaming simply by wishing so strongly—
なった から ね 諦め る はず ない その ステージ は きっと そこ に ある ！
Now that it's a dream, there's no way I'll give up; that stage is surely right there!
一緒に 一緒に 目指し たい の 景色 を 一緒に 一緒に 作り たい の
I want us to aim for the scenery together, I want us to create it together!
そう だ から しっかり ピット し て ！ マーマレード 私 がんばる よ
That's why I'll snap into it! Marmalade! I'm gonna do my best,
がんばる から ね よっしゃ ！ get up ！ stand up ！ run up ！ grow up ！
because I'll work hard! Alright! Get up! Stand up! Run up! Grow up!
みんながこうやってコメントを繋いでくれたから
Everyone connected your comments like this,
私は5年間ここに立っていられるよ 本当にありがとう！
so I've been able to stand here for 5 years. Thank you so much!
ピットして！マーマレード ピットして！マーマレード
Pitto Shite! Marmalade! Pitto Shite! Marmalade!
はい！というわけで、ピットして！マーマレード 初めて披露しました！
Yes! And with that, we performed "Pitto Shite! Marmalade" for the first time!
いやー、ピットして！マーマレード 初めて披露しましたー！やったー！
Man, we performed "Pitto Shite! Marmalade" for the first time! Yay!
ごめんなさい、ちょっと落ち着いて、ごめんなさい！走りたくなっちゃって！
I'm sorry, let me calm down, sorry! I just wanted to run!
そしてここでね、一応発表がある。今日は駆け足なんだ。発表することが多いんだ。
And here, I actually have an announcement. Today is rushed. There are a lot of things to announce.
ということで、活動5周年記念企画の1つ、soraSongグランプリっていうのがあったんですけど
So, one of our 5th-anniversary anniversary projects was the soraSong Grand Prix,
皆さん覚えてますかね？そらともさんからオリジナル楽曲を募集させていただくっていうやつなんですけど
do you all remember? It's where we invited original song submissions from Soratomos,
なんとね、噂によると50曲以上集まったらしいんですよ。
and apparently, rumor has it that over 50 songs were gathered!
ありがとうございます！そしてですね、その中の一曲を実わ…えー、最優秀ということで選ばせていただきました。
Thank you very much! And actually, out of those songs, we chose one as the grand prize winner... um...
今回選ばせていただいた曲がですね、じゃーん！
The song chosen this time is... ta-da!
え、komoさんという方の「ケ・セラ・ソラ！」という曲をですね、なんと選ばせていただきました。素敵な曲ありがとうございます！
Um, we chose a song called "Ke Sera Sora!" by someone named komo. Thank you for the wonderful song!
そしてなんと今日、初披露、ま、ワンコーラスではあるんですけど、最優秀作品の「ケ・セラ・ソラ！」をですね、歌っちゃいたいなと思います。
And today for the first time—well, just for one chorus—I'd like to sing the winning work, "Ke Sera Sora!"
本当に初披露です！皆さんぜひぜひ初めての曲を聞いていってください！
It's truly a first-time performance! Everyone, please be sure to listen to this brand new song!
それではいきますかね？ふふっ、それでは聞いてください、「ケ・セラ・ソラ！」
Shall we go then? Hehe, then please listen to "Ke Sera Sora!"
「せーのっ！」「ケ・セラ・ソラ！」
"Ready, set!" "Ke Sera Sora!"
おはよう朝日日にもご挨拶
Good morning, greeting the morning sun today too.
…ってあれ？ウソ！もうこんな時間！？
...Huh? No way! It's already this late?!
午後から予定あるのにすぐに支度をしなくちゃ
I have plans this afternoon, I need to get ready right away!
慌てて飛び出して気づく
Rushing out and realizing,
こっちじゃなーいっ！ここどこ！？
"Not this way! Where am I?!"
トラブルばっかり転んで起きての毎日です
Every day is full of trouble, falling down and getting back up.
おはよう 朝日に 今日も ご挨拶
Good morning, greeting the morning sun today as well.
…って あれ？ ウソ！ もうこんな時間！？
...Wait, huh? No way! It's already this late?!
午後から予定あるのに すぐに支度をしないと
Even though I have plans this afternoon, I need to get ready right away.
いってきまーす！
I'm heading out!
慌てて飛び出して 気付く
Flustered as I rush out, I realize
こっちじゃなーいっ！ ここどこ！？
This isn't the right way! Where am I?!
助けて 安肝～っ！
Help me, Ankimo~!
トラブルばっか転んで起きるの毎日です
Every day is full of trouble, tripping and getting back up.
何でも思い通りとか そんなおいしい話はないけど
Like everything going just as planned—there's no such convenient story, but
心の曇り空を晴らす合言葉 唱えたらね
when I chant the magic word to clear away the cloudy skies in my heart,
ほら、快晴でしょ？
look, it's clear skies, right?
ずっと皆に届けたい 歌もダンスも元気も
I want to always reach everyone with songs, dance, and energy.
きっと同じ空の下 笑顔も分け合えるよ
Surely, under the same sky, we can share our smiles too.
ちょっと疲れてしまうときも 涙が出そうになるときも
Even when I get a little tired, even when tears are about to fall,
いつもの魔法の言葉 今日も ケセラセラのそら
today too, with my usual magic words: Que Sera Sora.
せーのっ！
Ready, set!
ケ・セラ・ソラ！
Que Sera Sora!
ときに愛をちょ 君の空をちょ
Give a little love to Toki, give your sky to her!
wanna be your superstar
目標リストを更新しなくちゃ
Gotta update my target list!
昨日の希望(めい)は通過点なのさ
Yesterday's hopes are just stepping stones.
奇跡みたいな あの瞬間(とき)だってさ
Even that miraculous moment
超えて超えて超えて行くんだ
we're gonna surpass, surpass, and go beyond!
ファーストエイム は get to the next stage
First aim is get to the next stage.
コードネーム は 170907
Codename is 170907.
デイリームリームに浸ってないで
Don't just get lost in daydreams,
come on!! hurry up!!
every time every day 止まらないでしょ
every time every day, you won't stop, right?
ブレーキが効かないこのアタシと
With me, whose brakes just don't work,
ずっと一緒にいてちょうだい
stay together with me forever!
あなただけの wanna be your superstar
Your very own wanna be your superstar!
wanna wanna wanna wanna wanna be a superstar
ときに愛をちょだい 君の空をちょだい
Give a little love to Toki, give your sky!
キラキラ光って大きくなれ
Shine brightly and grow bigger,
虹色のわ あらんのわ
in a rainbow-colored world around the world!
悔しい日もあったね 一緒に涙したね
There were frustrating days, too; we cried together,
あの日があるから今がある ついてきて！ (ok!)
but because of those days, we have today. Come along! (OK!)
ときに愛をちょ 君の空をちょ
Give a little love to Toki, give your sky,
ずっと一緒にいてちょうだい
stay together with me forever!
あなただけの wanna be your superstar
Your very own wanna be your superstar!
wanna wanna wanna wanna wanna be a superstar
ときに愛をちょだい 君の空をちょだい
Give a little love to Toki, give your sky!
キラキラ光って大きくなれ
Shine brightly and grow bigger,
虹色のわ あらんのわ
in a rainbow-colored world around the world!
悔しい日もあったね 一緒に涙したね
There were frustrating days, too; we cried together,
あの日があるから今がある ついてきて！ (ok!)
but because of those days, we have today. Come along! (OK!)
ときに愛をちょ 君の空をちょ
Give a little love to Toki, give your sky,
ずっと一緒にいてちょうだい
stay together with me forever!
あなただけの wanna be your superstar
Your very own wanna be your superstar!
wanna wanna wanna wanna wanna be a superstar
私達の未来は out of control
Our future is out of control!
絶滅危機 の フェーズ へ 暴走中
Running wild toward an extinction-level phase.
誰が救うんだ
Who's gonna save us?
拒否ってる暇はないんだ
We don't have time to refuse!
やるんだ やるんだ やるしかないんだ
We gotta do it, we gotta do it, we have no choice!
恐れる気持ちは皆同じだ 怯んで振り返るのアタシもだ
Everyone feels scared, and so do I, looking back in fear.
でもそんな時こその合言葉 every time every day 止まらないでしょ
But even then, our magic words: every time every day, we won't stop, right?
最高 of the year にしてあげるわ 輝ける in our lives にしよう
I'll make it the best of the year, let's make it shine in our lives!
あなただけの wanna be your superstar
Your very own wanna be your superstar!
wanna wanna wanna wanna wanna be a superstar
ときに愛をちょだい 君の空をちょだい
Give a little love to Toki, give your sky!
ギンギン歌って夢を奏でて
Sing passionately and play our dreams,
虹色のわ あらんのわ
in a rainbow-colored world around the world!
無限に夢を発信 君がいれば安心
Broadcasting dreams infinitely, as long as you're here I'm at ease.
君と会えたから今がある ありがとう！ (ありがとう！)
Because I met you, I have today. Thank you! (Thank you!)
ずっと愛をちょ ずっと空をちょ
Always give a little love, always give a little sky,
そらとともに lets's go!! (lets's go!!)
along with Sora, let's go!! (let's go!!)
ときに愛をちょだい 君の空をちょだい
Give a little love to Toki, give your sky!
ギンギン歌って夢を奏でて
Sing passionately and play our dreams,
虹色のわ あらんのわ
in a rainbow-colored world around the world!
無限に夢を発信 君がいれば安心
Broadcasting dreams infinitely, as long as you're here I'm at ease.
君と会えたから今がある ありがとう！ (ありがとう！)
Because I met you, I have today. Thank you! (Thank you!)
ずっと愛をちょ ずっと空をちょ
Always give a little love, always give a little sky,
そらとともに lets's go!! (lets's go!!)
along with Sora, let's go!! (let's go!!)
ときに愛をちょ 君の空をちょ
Give a little love to Toki, give your sky,
ずっと一緒にいてちょうだい
stay together with me forever!
あなただけの wanna be your superstar
Your very own wanna be your superstar!
wanna wanna wanna wanna wanna be a superstar
ときに愛をちょ 君の空をちょ
Give a little love to Toki, give your sky,
ずっと一緒にいてちょうだい
stay together with me forever!
あなただけの wanna be your superstar
Your very own wanna be your superstar!
wanna wanna wanna wanna wanna be a superstar
宇宙の果ての星座を 君と探し当てたい
I want to find the constellations at the edge of the universe with you.
最初の上陸は 君と挑みたい
I want to challenge our first landing together with you.
一つずつ思い出を作って 一つずつ今を積み重ねて
Making memories one by one, piling up the present one by one.
同じ過去 同じ今 同じ未来 いくつできるだろう
How many same pasts, same presents, and same futures can we make?
ときに愛をちょだい 君の空をちょだい
Give a little love to Toki, give your sky!
キラキラ光って大きくなれ
Shine brightly and grow bigger,
虹色のわ あらんのわ
in a rainbow-colored world around the world!
悔しい日もあったね 一緒に涙したね
There were frustrating days, too; we cried together,
あの日があるから今がある ついてきて！ (ok!)
but because of those days, we have today. Come along! (OK!)
ときに愛をちょ 君の空をちょ
Give a little love to Toki, give your sky,
ずっと一緒にいてちょうだい
stay together with me forever!
あなただけの wanna be your superstar
Your very own wanna be your superstar!
wanna wanna wanna wanna wanna be a superstar
ときに愛を ちょ 君の空を ちょ
Give love sometimes, give me your sky sometimes
wanna be your superstar
目標リストを 更新しなきゃ
Got to update my goal list
昨日の夢は 通過点なのさ
Yesterday's dreams are just stepping stones
奇跡みたいな あの瞬間だってさ
Even that miraculous moment
超えて 超えて 超えて 行くんだ
I'll surpass, surpass, surpass and go beyond
ファーストエイムは get to the next stage
First aim is to get to the next stage
コーデネームは 170907
Codename is 170907
デイドリームに 浸ってないで
Don't get lost in daydreams
come on! hurry up!
every time every day 止まれ ないぞ
Every time, every day, we won't stop
ブレーキが 効かない このアタシと
With this brakes-off me
ずっと一緒いてちょうだい
Please stay with me forever
あなただけの i wanna be your superstar
I wanna be your exclusive superstar
wanna wanna wanna wanna wanna be a superstar
ときに 愛を ちょ 君の空を ちょ
Give love sometimes, give me your sky sometimes
キラキラ 光って 大きくなあれ
Sparkle brightly and grow big
虹色の輪 around the world
A rainbow ring around the world
悔しい日もあったね 一緒に泣いたね
There were frustrating days, we cried together
あの日があるから 今がある
Because we have those days, we have today
ついてきて! ok!
Follow me! Okay!
ときに 愛を ちょ 君の空を ちょ
Give love sometimes, give me your sky sometimes
そらとともに let's go!
Along with Sora, let's go!
up up up up up clap clap clap
はい！ということで、そらちゃんの『消えないソナタ』と
Yes! So, Tokino Sora's "Kienai Sonata" and...
え、全16曲！そらなのときにしてどうだった？
Uh, all 16 songs! How was it during Sora no Toki?
ときに愛をちょうだい！はい！はい！
Give me love sometimes! Yes! Yes!
ということで、いやあ、楽しかったかな、みんな？
So, man, I wonder if everyone had fun?
いや今回はね、上がる曲をいっぱい歌いたいなと思って、今ちょっと喋りながら若干後悔をしている自分がいる
Well, this time I wanted to sing lots of hype songs, and as I'm talking now, I sort of regret it a little bit...
すごい息が切れてるなと思っているね。
Thinking, "Man, I'm totally out of breath."
ねえ。でも、みんなが楽しそうで、すごく嬉しい！やったー！
Right? But everyone looks like they're having fun, I'm so happy! Yay!
みんなみんなぜひぜひいっぱい聴いて楽しんでね！いぇーい！
Everyone, please be sure to listen lots and enjoy! Yay!
はい、というわけで、このあとは、なんとゲストパートだよ！
Yes, so after this, it's actually the guest part!
私もお着替えしてこなくちゃ！
I gotta go change my outfit too!
同じ未来を見 ていたい
We want to see the same future
あの夢手にしたい
And make that dream our own
それぞれ違った ココロで走れ go!
Running with our different hearts, go!
どこを見ても 真っ暗な場所に芽生えていた
Even in pitch darkness, sprouts of hope emerged
ほんの小さな 希望にこの瞳 奪われていた
Captivated by just a tiny spark of hope
不安で揺れる心を 上手にチューニングして
Tuning our trembling hearts of anxiety
ほんの小さな 勇気を振り絞っていたよ
Gathering up just a tiny bit of courage
ShinySmilyStory 2022ver. 作詞：金丸歴史 作曲：中野領太 編曲：秋浦智裕
[Shiny Smily Story 2022 ver. / Lyrics: Kanamaru Rashi / Music: Nakano Ryota / Arrangement: Akiura Tomohiro]
諦めの文字 デリートして進む
Deleting words of surrender, we press on
苦しいとき もう私はひとりじゃないから
When it gets tough, I'm no longer alone
だからもっと 夢追いかけたい
That's why I want to chase my dreams even more
ワクワク 止まらない
The excitement won't stop
想像超えてくる 世界見せてあげる
We'll show you a world that surpasses imagination
アクセスしてみたい
We want to try accessing it
後悔なんてそうさせない
We won't let you have any regrets
それぞれ違った ココロで走れ go!
Running with our different hearts, go!
仮想の空に 輝く眩しい想いは
The dazzling feelings shining in the virtual sky
見たことのない光を 現実にするよ
Turning unseen light into reality
いつも聞こえるエールは ここにキャプチャーして
Capturing the cheers we always hear right here
また新しい光を 探したくなるよ
Makes us want to search for a new light once more
君の笑顔は 保存して進む
Saving your smile in our hearts, we press forward
悲しい時に見返すよ 力が湧くから
Looking back at it when sad, it gives us strength
胸を張って夢追いかけたい
We want to chase our dreams with our heads held high
奇跡の物語
A miraculous story
一緒に作ろう 終わらない夢を
Let's create together an endless dream
誰一人欠かさない 愛が舞い立ったこの世界
In this world where love dances, leaving no one behind
それぞれ違った ココロで彩れ
Coloring it with our individual hearts
悲しいときも 寂しいときもある
There are times when we're sad, times when we're lonely
信じ合えるものがある
Yet there's something we can believe in together
忘れずにこの鼓動 鳴らし続けたい
We want to keep this heartbeat ringing without forgetting
終わらない世界に 溢れ出るよ笑顔達
Smiles overflow into this endless world
憧れの舞台 立ちたい
We want to stand on the stage of our dreams
らしく輝きたい
We want to shine as ourselves
時には涙して また笑い合いたい
Sometimes shedding tears, then laughing together again
同じ未来を見 ていたい
We want to see the same future
あの夢手にしたい
And make that dream our own
踏み出そう 奇跡の一歩を
Let's take a miraculous first step forward
息切らせして 夢追いかけたい
Out of breath, we want to chase our dreams
ワクワク 止まらない
The excitement won't stop
想像超えてくる 世界見せてあげる
We'll show you a world that surpasses imagination
アクセスしてみたいな
We'd love for you to try accessing it
後悔なんて ここにない
There are no regrets to be found here
それぞれ違った ココロで作る world
Creating a world with our individual hearts
同じ未来を 見ていたい
We want to see the same future
あの夢 手にしたい
And make that dream our own
それぞれ違った 心で走れ go!
Running with our different hearts, go!
どこを見ても 真っ暗な場所に
No matter where we looked in the pitch darkness
芽生えていた ほんの小さな
A tiny hope had sprouted
希望にこの瞳 奪われていた
Captivating our eyes
不安で揺れる心を 上手にチューニングして
Tuning our trembling hearts of anxiety
ほんの小さな勇気を 振り絞っていたよ
Gathering up just a tiny bit of courage
諦めの文字 デリートして進む
Deleting words of surrender, we press on
苦しいとき もう私はひとりじゃないから
When it gets tough, I'm no longer alone
だからもっと 夢追いかけたい
That's why I want to chase my dreams even more
ワクワク止まらない
The excitement won't stop
想像超えてくる 世界見せてあげる
We'll show you a world that surpasses imagination
アクセスしてみたい
We want to try accessing it
後悔なんてそうさせない
We won't let you have any regrets
それぞれ違った ココロで走れ go!
Running with our different hearts, go!
悲しいときも 寂しいときも
Times of sadness, times of loneliness
信じ合えるものがある
There is something we can believe in together
忘れずにこの鼓動 鳴らし続けたい
We want to keep this heartbeat ringing without forgetting
終わらない世界に 溢れ出るよ笑顔達
Smiles overflow into this endless world
憧れの舞台立ちたい
We want to stand on the stage of our dreams
らしく輝きたい
We want to shine as ourselves
時には涙して また笑い合いたい
Sometimes shedding tears, then laughing together again
それぞれ違ったココロでつくる world
Creating a world with our individual hearts
同じ未来を見たい
I want to see the same future,
あの夢 手に入れたい
I want to make that dream mine.
それぞれ違ったセヤ
Run with our respective hearts, go!
どこを見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えてた
In pitch-black darkness, a tiny hope sprouted.
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳奪われた
This gaze was captured by just a tiny glimmer of hope.
不安で揺れる心を上手くチューニングして
Tuning my trembling heart just right,
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
I mustered up a little bit of courage.
諦めの文字デリートして進む
Deleting resignation from my mind, I press forward.
苦しいときもう私はひとりじゃないから
Even in tough times, I'm no longer alone,
だからもっと夢追いかけたい
So I want to chase my dreams even more!
ワクワク止まらない
My excitement just won't stop,
想像越えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world that surpasses imagination!
アクセスしてみたい
I want to access it,
後悔なんてそうさせない
I won't let you have any regrets!
それぞれ違ったココロで走れ go!
Run with our respective hearts, go!
仮想の空に輝く眩しい想いは
Brilliant feelings shining in the virtual sky,
見たことのない光を現実に出会う
Bringing unseen light into reality.
いつも聞こえるエールをここにキャッチして
Capturing every cheering voice we always hear,
また新しい光を探したくなるよ
We want to keep searching for brand-new light.
君の笑顔は保存して進む
Preserving your smiles as we press forward,
悲しい時に見返すよ力が湧くから
Looking back when sad gives us strength.
胸を張って夢追いかけたい
Chest puffed out, we want to chase our dreams!
奇跡の物語
A miraculous story weaved together.
わあ！
Whoa!
というわけで今回のスペシャルゲストは...
So, our special guest for today is...
0期生のみんなだよー！
Everyone from the 0th generation!
いや楽しかったね！
That was so much fun!
エモすぎた！
So emotional!
息つく暇もないよ
I couldn't catch my breath!
みんな頑張った！みんな頑張った！
We all worked really hard!
あのサードフェスのライブ直後でね！
That was right after our 3rd Fes performance!
わいわいしてたね！
We were so pumped up!
もう6年目か！
It's already our 6th year, huh?
そうだよ、今日から6年目！
That's right, starting today!
すごい早い！
That's so fast!
なんかもう5年もやったのかっていう感覚があるわ。
It feels like we just finished our 5th year.
そうはもう5年です。
Right, it's been 5 years.
でもさ、なのになのに
Even so, getting together like this...
この記念枠とかで0期生が集まるのって
For this 5th anniversary, getting 0th gen together...
初めて！初めて！
Is actually the first time!
えー！そうなんだ！確かに！
Really? That's surprising!
なかなか集まんないよね。
It's surprisingly rare to get everyone together.
もうホロライブハマったばかりの人はなんだこのメンツって思ってるかもしれない。
People who got into Hololive recently might wonder why this lineup is special.
ゼロ期生を知らないのかも知れないんよね。
They might not even know about 0th gen!
なんだそれ、幻奏とかね！
And what's more, back then there was Gensou...
幻奏！そう、レジェンド！
Gensou! Right! Legend!
やり遂げたね。そう、なんきせいとかなくね。
We managed to pull it off, right?
あの、だってね、ファーストフェスか！
Because, after all, at 1st Fes...
ファーストフェスで一応ね、5人で一緒にステージ立ったんだけど。
At 1st Fes, 5 of us performed together on stage.
そうそうそう、その時はまだゼロ期生っていう名前が浸透して...
Back then, the name "0th Gen" hadn't even spread yet.
そう、なんかそれぞれソロ組みたいなね。
Right, everyone was like a solo unit!
そのデビュー組だった。
We were basically debut group members.
特にね、あんまりなんかしかもさ、名前が本当にいろいろあったから派閥が。
Especially since our names and branches were all so varied.
ゼロ期生？幻奏？ソロ組？みたいなね。
"0th Gen? Gensou? Solo unit?"
私たち自身の中の、中組だったから。
We were like the "in-between group."
そう、その時代を経て
Having gone through all those eras,
ここにみんな集まってね、ゼロ期生となるわけですよ！
Now we're all sitting here together as 0th Gen!
今日はね、あの節目っていうこともありますし、
Today is a milestone,
ずっとね、最初から一緒に頑張ってきたメンバーをゲストに呼びたいっていうので、
We wanted to call together the members who worked hard from the very beginning!
みんなでやっぱ、私たちの曲といえばSSSみたいなイメージが強くて、一緒にやりたいなと思ってやりました！
We wanted to capture that strong SSS image together!
2022年バージョン！
The 2022 version!
エモかったね！すごい。
It was so emotional!
エモさがさ、アップして、アップしたね！
The emotional level was definitely up!
よかった！
I'm so glad we did it.
でね、みんなでこういうアイドル衣装でね、はい、もう撮っちゃうって感じね。
And everyone taking photos together in idol outfits like this—
いっぱい写真撮って、撮って！
Taking so many photos!
珍しいんだぞ。本当に珍しい。
That's so rare, it's amazing!
次はね、猫のポーズ、みんなでポーズしよう！
Next, let's take a cat pose together!
せーの、にゃん！にゃん！にゃん！
Ready, set, nya!
写真が撮れたよ！
We got a great photo!
次は、次は、次は、何がいいかな？え、セクシーなポーズ？
What should our next pose be? Sexy pose?
3、2、1、はい！
3, 2, 1, pose!
みんな大体、普通に可愛くなっちゃうの！
Everyone ended up striking a cute pose instead!
みんな同じになっちゃうんだよね、なんか。なんだか、セクシー、セクシーマリンです！
We all ended up doing a cute pose naturally!
ほら、もうすぐ行くの？
Hey, are we going soon?
え、どうだろ？ まだ時間あるかね？
Huh, I wonder? Do we still have time?
配信画面なんだろう？
What's on the stream screen?
あずきちゃん！あずきちゃん、なんか
AZKi! AZKi, like...
ちょっとみんなまっすぐ並ぼ！
Hey everyone, let's line up straight!
みんなまっすぐならぼ！
Everyone line up straight!
縦に！縦に！縦に！
In a line! Vertically! Vertically!
一番後ろ、一番後ろ！
The very back, the very back!
で、中腰ね、私が。あ、ちょっと、ちょっと、お、みんな見える？
And crouching down, me. Oh, wait, wait, oh, can everyone see?
身長高っ！
You're so tall!
So tall!
小さいのに何で後ろなんだ、お前！
Why are you in the back even though you're small?!
ということでね、何か告知したいことがあるということで
So, as we have something to announce...
え、何ですか？ 何と？
Eh, what is it? What could it be?
今日はですね、今回、5周年を記念して、グッズをご用意しております！
Today, we have prepared goods to commemorate our 5th anniversary!
画像、画像！
The image, the image!
どれ、どれ？
Which one, which one?
はい、今回のグッズはこちらです！活動5周年記念ということでですね
Yes, here are our goods for this time! To commemorate the 5th anniversary...
記念ボイス1種と記念グッズ3種類をご用意しております！
We have prepared 1 commemorative voice and 3 types of goods!
まず1つ目は、こちらです！ランダムアクリルキーホルダー！
First is this! A random acrylic keychain!
今回はですね、イラストいかき先生に描いていただきました！
This time, the illustration was drawn by Ikaki-sensei!
そう、あの、初期からずっと私の、ね、最初のお世話になっている方なんだけど
Yes, someone who has taken care of me since the very beginning...
その方にイラストを描いていただきました！どれもかわいいから、みんな見てもらえると嬉しいな！
drew the illustrations for us! They're all so cute, I'd be happy if everyone checked them out!
そして次がこちら！Tシャツ！カセ先生という方に描いていただきました！
And next is this! A T-shirt! Illustrated by someone named Kase-sensei!
え、でも、でもね、おしゃれかもしれない。おしゃれ！おしゃれ！
Eh, but, you know, it might be stylish. Stylish! Stylish!
なんか、どんぐりが3つ連なってるようにしか...
It looks like three acorns linked together...
あれはピーナッツだ！ピーナッツ、ピーナッツ、ピーナッツだ！
That's peanuts! Peanuts, peanuts, peanuts!
あ、触覚じゃないんだ、あれは。触覚じゃない。
Ah, those aren't antennae. Not antennae.
なんかちょっとおしゃれにしようかなと思って。いや、おしゃれ、おしゃれ！おしゃれだよ！
I thought about making it a bit stylish. No, stylish, stylish! It's stylish!
これ、次の自由研究してる時に着たい！
I want to wear this when doing my next independent research!
そして次はこちら！ぬんぬんぬいぐるみ！サイズは約H170×W250×D170mm。
And next is this! Nun-nun plushie! Size is approx. H170 x W250 x D170mm.
かわいいでしょ。なんか、もふもふしたものが作りたいなと思って、ぬんぬんで作っていただきました！
Cute, right? I wanted to make something fluffy, so they made it as a Nun-nun!
なんか、このぬんぬん、あんきもにそっくりすぎて...そう、あんきもじゃなくて、ぬんぬんなの！浮いているけど、よろしくね！
This Nun-nun looks so much like Ankimo... Wait, it's not Ankimo, it's Nun-nun! It's floating, but please treat it well!
大人気のみこち！ほら、やった！くれた！ま、ま、見て、あんきもそっくり！
Super popular Mikochi! Look, she did it! She gave it to me! W-w-look, it looks just like Ankimo!
お願い、もっと買って！買って！
Please, buy more! Buy them!
わあーい！よしよしよしよし
Yay! Good, good, good, good!
よしよしよしよしよし、どんどんキャラが増えていっちゃう現象が起こっておりますが
Good, good, good, good, a phenomenon where characters keep increasing is happening, but
こっちでもよろしくねということで、はい！
please look favorably on this side too, so yeah!
絶対ゲットしたい！
I definitely want to get it!
そしてそして、まあこれは全部合わさったものもね、ありますね。どん！
And then, well, there's also the complete set containing everything. Boom!
はい、どん！
Yeah, boom!
はい、こちらがですね、えー、あ、んっと、このボイス単品っていうのもありまして、シチュエーションボイスですね。うんうんうんうん。
Yes, this is, um, oh, right, there is also this voice-only item, the situation voice. Uh-huh, uh-huh, uh-huh.
えー、うん、逆金になってるからな、そう、それと秋服のお買い物デート！
Um, yeah, since it's a reward, right, a shopping date in autumn clothes with Sora!
お買い物、お買い物！シチュエーションね、ボイスもね、えー、しゃべりましたのでぜひぜひよろしくお願いします！
Shopping, shopping! The situation voice, um, I spoke it, so please definitely check it out!
はい、はーい！
Yes, yes!
そして、フルセットがこちらです！
And then, here is the full set!
はい、え、フルセットの特典としては
Yes, um, as a perk for the full set,
こちらのですね、秋下ろしのものに、え、箔押しのサインをつけてお届けしますので、よろしくお願いします！
we'll deliver this newly illustrated item with a foil-stamped signature, so please look forward to it!
欲しい！欲しい！
I want it! I want it!
と、いうわけで、告知コーナーでございましたのでよろしくお願いします！みんなゲットしてくれよなー！
So that was the information corner, thank you! Everyone go get it!
ね、みんなも出てきたからまたアプリーくらいやるかい？やりたいやりたい！
Hey, since everyone came out, should we play Appli again? We want to, we want to!
どうやって撮ろうとしたら、えっと、客席を背景にする？
How should we take it? Um, should we use the audience seats as the background?
あ、いいね、いいね！
Oh, that's nice, nice!
客席側に、あ、こうやってみんなでなんかいわゆる最後の
Toward the audience side, oh, like this, everyone doing the so-called final
あー、みんなで写真演出。
Ah, everyone doing a photo setup.
あ、ちょっと、ここだ！ここだ！ここだ！ここだ！
Ah, wait, here! Here! Here! Here!
はい、せーの！
Ready, set!
イェーイ！
Yay!
みんな見に来てくれて、ありがとー！
Thank you everyone for coming to see us!
すごいみんな振ってくれてる。イェーイ！
Everyone is waving so much. Yay!
大はしゃぎ！
Super excited!
かわいい！かわいい！
Cute! Cute!
あんきま、ぽくぬい。ぬぬぬぬあんきま
Ankima, pokunui. Nunununu ankima
ばかあんきま、ぽくぬい。ぬぬぬぬあんきま。
Stupid ankima, pokunui. Nunununu ankima.
仲良くなってる！いつの間にかあんきもに。なってって、なってって。イェーイ！
They've become close! Before we knew it, into Ankimo. Becoming, becoming. Yay!
おや、おや、おやと、そんなこと言ってる間に
Oh, oh, oh, while saying such things,
もう時間が来てしまいました！
the time has already come!
早いよー！
That's too fast!
みんなの方を向いて終わりにしよう、そしたら。あ、いいね！
Let's face the audience and end it, then. Oh, that's good!
こっちでもさししみみたいな感じの終わりにしようか。みんな見えてるしこれで。
Let's end it with kind of a Sashimi-like vibe here too. Since everyone can see us with this.
とにかくゲットしなさい、ほんとに！すぐね！
Anyway, definitely go get it! Right away!
やだ、やだ！離れたくない！離れたくない！あきんで！
No, no! I don't want to part ways! I don't want to leave! Akinde!
はい、今日のスペシャルコラボも、ぜろきせーの、みんなでしたー！
Yes, today's special collaboration was also with the 0-ki-sei, everyone!
イェーイ！ありがとー！
Yay! Thank you!
はい、というわけで、ぬんぬんがまだ残ってる。
Yes, so nunnun is still remaining here.
ぬんぬんちゃんがここにいますが、
Nunnun-chan is here, but
え、本日はありがとうございます！
um, thank you very much for today!
え、新曲などをたくさん披露させていただいたり、ゼロ期生のね、みんなと一緒にライブをしたり、もう最高のご周年のです。
Um, getting to showcase many new songs and others, performing live with everyone from the 0th generation, it's just the best 5th anniversary.
え、5周年っていうのは、なんか正直あんまり実感がなくて、こうやってみんながおめでとうってたくさんの人にこう見ていただけて
Um, a 5th anniversary, honestly doesn't feel quite real yet, but seeing how many people are congratulating me and watching,
やっと今ちょっと、ちょっとずつ実感をしてきたなっていう感じがします。
I finally feel like I'm starting to realize it little by little now.
えー、これからね、秋にはね、私もライブを控えておりまして、え、また頑張っていきたいなと思ってるんですが、
Um, from now on, in autumn, I have a live concert coming up too, and I want to work hard again,
これからもね、この後もいろいろありますから、え、ご周年、あ、ソロライブもご周年なので、どんどん頑張っていきたいなって思ってます。
but since there are various things coming up after this too, um, the 5th anniversary, oh, the solo live is also for the 5th anniversary, so I want to keep doing my best.
えー、そうですね、なんか、こうやってみんながね、パチパチパチパチってしてる中で、こうね、最初は歌うのも緊張してたんですけど、今ではみんなのコメントのおかげで楽しく歌うことができています。
Um, well, in the midst of everyone clapping like this, um, at first I was nervous about singing too, but now, thanks to everyone's comments, I am able to sing happily.
え、5年間、え、いろいろありましたが、本当に今ここに来て、ここにいてよかったなって思ってますし、これから先ももっともっと頑張っていきたいなって思っています。
Um, for 5 years, um, there were various things, but I truly feel so glad that I came here and am here now, and I want to work even harder going forward.
なので、これからもちょっと 仲良くしてね。よろしくお願いします！
So, please continue to get along with me forever. Thank you very much!
えー、最後の曲はそんな気持ちを込めて、アルバムの中から1つ、1つ、1つ、1つ、1つ...
Um, the last song puts all those feelings into it, one by one from the album...
かっこよく終わろうと思ったのに！そんな、そんな、あ、噛み噛み！
I thought I'd end it coolly! Such, such, ah, stumbling over my words!
や、そういう気持ちを込めて一曲お送りさせていただきますので、ぜひぜひ歌っていこうかなと思います。
I've put those feelings into this song, so I hope you'll sing along with me.
では、行きますかね。
Well then, shall we get started?
みんな準備はいいかな？
Are you all ready?
最後の曲聴いてください。
Please listen to the final song.
「ユメソラ☆ファンファーレ」！
Yumezora☆Fanfare!
約束した今日の日のことを
The promise we made for today
一生忘れない そんな気がした
I felt I would never forget it as long as I live.
あの空の向こう側を 覗いてみたいなって
I've always wanted to peek beyond that sky,
覗き込んだ望遠鏡 宝探しみたいだ
peering through a telescope like treasure hunting.
「好き」が夢を叶えるって
They say that "love" makes dreams come true,
誰かが言ってた 思いっきり泣いたり
someone once said. Crying your eyes out,
笑ったりして
laughing out loud,
全速で前進でしょ！
full speed ahead, right!
あの夜明けが星空を追い越した時 流れる星が光った
When the dawn overtook the starry night, a shooting star shone bright.
一つだけ願うのなら 夢が叶う瞬間
If I could make just one wish: the moment my dream comes true,
そばにいてくれますか？ 見に行こう
will you stay by my side? Let's go see it.
ハッピーエンドのファンファーレ キラキラの未来へ
A happy ending fanfare, towards a sparkling future.
星に負けない光と 確かな希望 響かせて
Letting resonate a light that won't lose to the stars and true hope.
涙と涙が重なって空が明けるように
Just like tears mingling together to dawn the sky,
夢と夢がギュッと重なる瞬間を 奇跡と呼ぶんだ
calling the moment when dreams tightly intertwine a miracle.
終着点はいったって キミのその笑顔
No matter where the destination is, it's your smile.
遠回りしたけど出逢えたんだ
We took a detour, but we met.
一緒、一緒でしょう？
We're together, aren't we?
煌めく希望のメロディ 夢に愛に行こう
A sparkling melody of hope, let's go meet our dreams.
無数の星屑の中 見つけてくれてありがとう
Thank you for finding me among the countless stardust.
大切なキミへいつの日でも 一番に届けよう
To you, my precious one, no matter what day, let's deliver it first.
見てって 私 ここで 歌い続けること
Watch me keep singing right here,
約束するから
I promise you.
キミの声を 聞かせてよ
Let me hear your voice,
もっともっと近くで
closer, even closer.
道を照らす月のように （ずっとずっとずっと…）
Like the moon illuminating the path (always, always, always...)
みんな大好き！
I love you all!
ハッピーエンドのファンファーレ 盛大に讃えよう
A happy ending fanfare, let's praise it grandly.
見たことのない世界へ ステップ踏んで飛び出そう
Step out into a world you've never seen before and take flight.
笑顔と笑顔が重なって 虹がかかるように
Just like smiles intertwine to form a rainbow,
夢と夢がギュッと重なる瞬間を 奇跡と呼ぶんだ
calling the moment when dreams tightly intertwine a miracle.
行こうよ 夢空の向こうへ
Let's go beyond the sky of dreams.
本当に本当に ありがとうございました！
Thank you so very much!
そして最後に ここで皆さんにお知らせがあります
And finally, I have an announcement for you all!
先ほど18時には発表になってるんですけど、なんと！
Announced just at 6 PM, but... guess what?!
ときのそら 必見アニバーサリーライブ！
Tokino Sora's must-see anniversary live!
空と時のミルキーウェイ ワンマンライブの開催が決定しました！ありがとう！
Milky Way solo live is confirmed!
2022年11月19日土曜日、東京、かつしかシンフォニーヒルズ モーツァルトホールにて、
At Katsushika Symphony Hills Mozart Hall, Tokyo,
オンラインはいつも通りのスポンサーで、させていただきます。
online streaming will be held as usual.
今回も昼と夜の2公演です。
There will be two performances, day and night.
昼公演にはアフタートークもありますよ。
There will also be an after-talk for the day show.
チケットの発売はもう始まってます！
Ticket sales have already started!
そしてなんと初めての生バンドでのライブとなります！
This will be my first live with a live band!
みんなと一緒に素敵な思い出が作りたい！ぜひぜひみんな遊びに来てね！
Let's make wonderful memories! Please come join us!
そしてそして……！
And and...
このあとホロライブプロダクション5周年記念特番「ときののかけはし」が放送されます！
Afterwards, Hololive's 5th Anniversary special
私も出演して、谷郷社長と共演しておりますので、ぜひご覧ください！
I'll be appearing with CEO Tanigo, so check it out!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you for your support!
ありがとう、みんな！
Thank you everyone!